<document>
  <properties>
    <author email="brill@pappin.ca">Brill Pappin</author>
    <title>Installation</title>
  </properties>
  <!-- Optional HEAD element, which is copied as is into the XHTML <head> element -->
  <head>
  </head>
  <body>
	 <p>Please send improvments or questions about this documentation to <a href="mailto:xtracker@pappin.ca">xtracker@pappin.ca</a></p>
    <section name="Quick Start">
	 <subsection name="Set up your database">
	 	<p>See the <em>Requirements</em> section for databases that XTracker has been 
	 		tested on. Send in your success story if you choose another database and 
	 		I'll add it to the list.</p>
        <p>XTracker uses a database to store it's tickets and you will need to prepare 
        	the one you are using before you install the WAR file.</p>
        <p>Setup a new database for XTracker (something like "xtracker" would be 
        	obvious).</p>
        <p>Setup a new user that can access the new database. The user should have 
        	permission to create tables and indexes on that database as the application 
        	will attempt to set it up for you whe you first run it. Once the application 
        	is installed and running, you can restrict the database users permissions to 
        	select, insert, delete etc.</p>
     </subsection>
      
     <subsection name="Set up Java">
     	<p>See the <em>Requirements</em> section for the JDK version you should use.</p>
        <p>You must have java properly set up before you can run your servlet container. 
        	I will assume at this point that you know how to install Java on your machine 
        	and properly configure it. Let me know if I need to update this documentation 
        	and give an overview.</p>
     </subsection>
     
     <subsection name="Set up your application server">
     	<p>See the <em>Requirements</em> section for the application servers that have 
     		been tested.</p>
        <p>Install and configure your application server. XTracker is simply installed 
        	as any other WAR file would be.</p>
        <subsection name="Running for the first time">
        	<p>Once XTracker is running, the first person to access it should be the 
        		installer as that person will be required to input some configuration 
        		information  that the installer will know. You only have to do this 
        		once however and  XTracker will not allow the setup page to be run 
        		again.</p>
        	<p>You should be familiar with how to set properties for JDBC as you 
        		<strong>must</strong> enter them properly for XTrtacker to work.</p>
    	    <p>If you need to change its configuration manually (if for instance you 
    	    	don't configure JDBC properly), the config files are stored in the 
    	    	directory you where asked for on the setup page. Otherwise use the 
    	    	administration console built into the application.</p>
	    </subsection> 
	    <p>The admin password upon installation is "admin". <strong>Don't forget to 
	    	change it!</strong></p>  
     </subsection>
    </section>

    <section name="Setting up a Queue">
    	<p>Currently XTracker only supports POP3 access to the Queues. Future versions 
    		will have alternative methods of getting tickets into the system.</p> 
    	<p>To set up a new Queue, create the queue and give it an alias. The alias is a 
    		mail alias so you should create a main account for XTracker on your mail 
    		server and give it an alias that matches the queue alias.</p>
    	<p>You can change how often XTracker checks for incoming tickets by changing the 
    		cron property. Be carefule however as this is not a standard unix cron string. 
    		For more information on the cron string, see the Quartz project (Yes, the 
    		traling "?" is required).</p> 
    	<p>If you make a mistake and need to reset the cron, simply edit the 
    		mail.properties in your config directory. the original cron 
    		is: "0 * * * * ?" which mean to check for new mail every 60 seconds.</p>
    </section>
    
    <section name="Tips and Tricks">
    	<p>Make sure you set the "XTracker Context" to point to you installation. 
    		This URL will be used when sending out mail so that the users of the 
    		system can simply click through to a ticket.</p>
    </section>
  </body>
 </document>
